Podcasting 2.0 for January 30th, 2026,
episode 249. Put more cheese on it.
Well, hello, everybody.
Welcome to Podcasting 2.0.
It's that time of the week again,
and we're a little bit early.
Can you believe it?
Time to talk about all things podcasting.
This is where it really happens.
We are the only boardroom that
now runs entirely on Linux.
I'm Adam Curry here in the heart of
the Texas Hill Country and in Alabama,
the man who has a hard out
at least once a month.
Say hello to my friend on the other
end, the one, the only, Mr. Dave.
Okay, so, yeah, boardroom's
saying they can't hear me.
Oh, hold on a second.
Do you have me pot? Did you pot me down?
No, no, that's exactly what I thought
would happen. Hold on a second.
They can't hear you? You don't need
to hear Dave. What's your problem?
I mean, I'm just going to eat, so.
Hold on a second.
Yeah, Spurlock said,
no Dave on the street.
Hold on, I'm going to
disconnect and fix that.
I know exactly what's going on.
Hold on.
They'll be okay for a moment.
Oh, that's too funny. I know
exactly what it is. Hold on.
The whole show like that would
have been great, though.
Just you talking to yourself?
It'd be fantastic, yeah.
All I want to hear is
myself. Hold on. Where am I?
Okay, so this needs to be on this one.
Am I here?
Huh?
Do I exist?
I think you do.
Is it really me?
Let me see.
Where is it?
One, two, one, two, one, two.
No, that's not it. That's not it. Hold on.
You can, we're recording.
That's the good news.
Oh, would, does, do I go into the
recording or was it only you?
Yeah, no, you're, you're also
going into the recording.
Okay, well then we can just replay this
as the beginning of the show, as usual.
No, we're, we're just going to keep
everything exactly the same. Hold on.
Yeah, yeah, it's got to be because
this is part of the Linux experience.
This is exactly what the
Linux experience is.
Okay, let me see if this does it. Hold on.
Yeah, all right. Let me see.
All right, talk to me, Dave.
Hello, I'm talking to you, Adam.
No, I don't.
Can the boardroom hear me?
No, probably not.
No, I don't think so.
What is going on?
Can you, can you guys hear
David say something, Dave?
I'm saying something.
I'm also in the middle of eating
a, a grass-fed beef stick.
That's not it. Hold on.
Like Cotton Gin said, there
you are. He hears me.
Oh, Cotton Gin.
Cotton Gin.
Cotton Gin, you hear him now?
Only Cotton Gin. Nobody
else in the boardroom.
Oh, no, Dave.
Can you hear me?
No, Dave.
Well, daggone it.
Hold on.
One of these has got to be right.
Don't hear.
Cotton Gin.
Well, no, Cotton Gin can't hear me.
I need to talk to the boardroom.
Okay, let's see.
Boom, boom, boom, boom.
Wait.
Boom, boom.
Let's see.
Settings.
Oh, no.
This is, this is great.
So everything, everything works except.
Is this the test run for
NA is what I want to do?
Oh, yeah.
No, it's totally.
Okay.
Yeah, this is what I
expected and appreciate.
Yes.
Let's see.
Unfortunately, it seems
the whole thing seems to.
The problem is, but, but
is the problem here.
Hold on a second.
Hold on.
I can't get this thing to close.
Here we go.
Can you vibe code your way out of this?
Close.
Can I?
Say something.
Say something, Dave.
Hello.
I'm saying something.
I'm hearing.
Yeah, I think we got it.
Are you hearing yourself?
Yeah, I hear myself.
We, it says we hear Dave now,
just slightly time shifted.
Time shifted?
Time shifted.
Like, like, like from earlier?
There's no time shifting.
They hear, they heard me from, from like,
right at the beginning
of the show, I guess.
So, yes, we are completely
on Arch Linux today.
Okay.
This is like.
I'm going to.
Is this problem solved?
So I'm back.
Am I on the feed now?
No, you're back.
No, everyone hears.
I don't know what this
time shifting nonsense is.
Here, I'm going to post the picture.
Time shifting.
I'm going to post a picture of the setup.
Here we go.
Okay.
Post.
Upload.
There we go.
Okay.
There you go.
Yay.
All right.
You got me a.
This is, this is the setup.
I have in vibe coded it
myself in its entirety.
Yeah, baby.
Oh, that looks good.
So at the top, you've got.
Wow.
Eight players all mapped to the MIDI.
The.
Wait, wait, we're not recording.
We're not live.
Yeah, we are.
No, we're live.
But I've been, I've been recording the,
I've been, the recording has been working.
Oh, okay.
Well, I thought we were off the rip.
No, no, no.
Because this is, I mean, this is
perfect to leave that in there because,
because welcome to Linux.
Yeah, exactly.
It's a man.
So let me just tell you
what you're seeing here.
So at the top, you see eight players.
They're all mapped to my MIDI control.
I have the nano control two.
Okay.
So the play, stop, and dump buttons are
also all mapped to the MIDI controller.
If you click on the time, so
it starts with time left.
If you click on that, it turns green,
shows you how long it's been playing.
If you click on the title, it automatically
sends it to pre-fader listening.
So to a different, a different
interface on the Rodecaster.
If you left click, you can set
the outputs and do MIDI learn.
So then, you know, you can,
you just click on any button,
right click on any button, say
MIDI learn, and it maps it right away.
On the left.
Let me, let me, Daniel says he's still
hearing last week's episode on the stream.
No, he's not.
Hold on.
Congen said, and Congen said, yep.
All right.
I don't know.
How about now?
Be more, use, use your words.
You, I think, I think everything was
working, but I forgot to hit stream.
Okay.
Oh, is, this is, this is great.
There we go.
Now, now it's working.
Now, now we've got, yes.
Okay.
Now we've got, oh, that, okay.
So what I understand,
so when I disconnected,
the old 2.0 started
playing on the stream and
they, and they thought that we were live.
Wow.
That's meta.
That is super good.
This is, this is the Linux
way is what this is.
It's not just the Linux way.
It's the Omarchi way, baby.
That's the Omarchi, you throw it, you got,
you got a little bit of Omarchi, a little
bit of vibe code, doing some Linux,
add a Rodecaster, boom, podcast.
All right.
So let me explain it again.
Not everybody can hear me.
So I, I vibe coded this whole thing.
It's all done in Python using the QT
libraries for the, uh, for the interface.
So at the, at the top
you have eight players.
They're all mapped to my nano control to
MIDI controller, which has eight faders
and next to each fader,
there's three buttons.
So, um, the play button is, uh, is mapped
the stop button and the dump button.
Uh, you can set in and out points, which
I'll, you know, I always do for the,
uh, like the end of show ISO that we use.
So I can, as I can just set a little
clip to play, you click on the,
the time remaining, it turns green, told,
it tells you how much time is left.
Click on the, I don't see time remain.
What is, where is time remaining?
At the top, you see the
red numbers, the red.
Oh, oh, oh yeah.
Okay.
I see.
Yeah.
So if you click on it, you mean that.
If you click on that, it turns green
to see how long it's been playing.
Sometimes I want that.
If I click on the, um, on
the title of the clip,
it turns red and now it's in PFL mode.
So pre-fader listening sends
it to a different interface.
And if I right click, I can set the
global outputs for PFL and per program.
And I can also, you can right click on
any element and you can map it to MIDI.
So, you know, gone are the
days of doing that manually.
I'm dragging things in or whatever.
Yeah.
On the left, this is where
I spent a lot of time.
On the left is, uh, the file browser
and so you can, uh, select the library.
So it just shows the full, so like
one folder shows the full folder,
but then you search the library
and it's lightning fast.
So it's already, it's already.
Why is it lightning fast?
Because you have an, you have
a local indexer or something?
Yeah.
It indexes, it indexes, saves
a huge JSON index file.
And when you start it up again, it
re-indexes, sees if anything's going on,
you can re-index it manually,
but it's re- cause it, uh,
the indexing is only done
on file names cause all
my file names are what,
what the clip contains.
So, so like when I send you a clip,
do you rename it to something
that makes sense to you?
No, no, I just put it into the,
into the, the bin for that show.
Okay.
Um, I don't have to, I can
drag and drop the clips,
but I can just click on it once and
automatically selects the, the
next player, uh, and loads it up.
On the right hand side is the, the cart wall
and you can say, cart wall, same thing.
You can, you can search
in the library and then
drag and drop it over to the cart wall.
And they have little volume
sliders and those are
controlled just by hovering the mouse over
the cart that's playing.
And then you can use the mouse
wheel, uh, like the opener, right?
I use that for the opener.
Just, it's just as easy since
I'm already clicking on it.
Um, what does the mouse wheel do?
Oh, that, that, that control like
this levels controls the volume.
Oh, no, that's so, oh, that's so slick.
Yeah.
So you don't have to have two hands.
You can just use one hand.
That, and that works at the top in those,
in, in the, the things across the top too.
Does the mouse wheel
also do those volumes?
Yes.
But, uh, but, but I, I like, that's the
ones I like using map to, uh, to MIDI.
That's a lot easier.
Cause you can, you know, cause you already
have your hand for the start button.
So it's all, it's kind of one hand.
I can always do something
else with my other hand.
Yes, you can.
So, so the tough part was mapping all of
the, the USB outputs on the road caster.
And the way you do it is you put the
road caster into multi-track mode.
And, um, so now you have 12 tracks and
then using pipe wire, which is, this is,
I mean, before it was Jack, you know,
I think that was the, you know,
Jack routing and all this stuff
that never really worked for me.
Um, now that, now that
pipe wire is in existence,
you just write a little script,
um, that, uh, what is it called?
A pipe wire router or something.
I'm not quite sure.
It's, it's just a small
script you add into the
config file and then it
sees the road caster
and says, Oh, okay, good.
I know what this is.
And it brings up the three interfaces.
The only thing which I just discovered is,
so it has USB one, USB two and USB chat.
That's what we have on the road caster.
What I've discovered it, it has, uh,
switched the naming of
USB chat to USB one main.
And that's why, well,
that, that's intuitive.
Well, yeah.
So I've, I've got to go in and that's
just, it did that automatically,
but it's just wrong.
So I've got to change that.
Um, then the biggest problem was as we,
as people on the stream
heard was getting, getting,
but the streaming tool known as
getting, but is always the beginning,
but is it's been
a problem since I was 13 years old,
but, but I finally loaded up, but, um,
and same confusion with the,
uh, uh, with the interface.
I guess I selected the wrong interface.
Um, really the, the biggest thing that's,
that's hampered me is the
recording tool because
I really, I mean, my workflow
for no agenda includes
a lot of editing and I use Hindenburg
pro is what, what I've all,
what I've been using for years.
And I really love it
because you can scrub back
and forth real quick
using keyboard commands
and then you hit I for, for
in, in point O for out.
Um, you just do, you know, the
regular X to, uh, to cut a piece,
cut a region or D you
would delete and I have tried audacity.
They've ruined audacity.
They screwed up audacity big time.
And, uh, so I'm using ocean
audio, O C E N ocean audio.
So you, so there's no Hindenburg.
It's, it's Mac and windows,
but there's no Linux.
No.
Oh, well you can go on the forums and
yeah, man, you can run it with wine.
Sure.
Yeah.
You may not be able to actually, um,
authenticate your copy with
your key, but you can run it.
Okay.
Yeah.
So that's not going to work.
Um, and, and so, yeah, so it
right now fully, I read and,
and just to add to this, this is
all running on the surface pro six.
So I'm running all of this.
Uh, I have the, the main, you know, it's
the surface pro is the secondary screen.
I have an HDMI big screen
in front of my face.
That's what I've got everything loaded on.
Uh, I was on board with you a hundred
percent until, until you, well,
but that was the dev
box because I just wanted to, you know,
cause I had this thing laying around anyway.
I'm like, let me just, I mean, it
runs, it only has one USB output.
So I have a dock connected to it,
which, Oh, this is getting worse.
Oh yeah.
This is even worse.
You're going to have to transfer
this onto a different box.
It's even better.
It has.
So it's a USB C with an adapter
into USB three into the surface.
I'm running, I'm running the,
the display port out into the
HDMI monitor and connected to
the hub is mouse keyboard,
uh, external drive,
which is where all the
clips are stored and
the, uh, uh, and the, the two USB
connectors for the road caster.
It works though.
I'm blown away.
I give this thing nine weeks before,
before this machine just before I,
before I wake up
on a show, on an NA show day and I
have a text from you saying, Hey,
windows gives me this boot message.
What's wrong?
What do you mean?
No, I'm not using windows anymore.
What are you talking about?
It's all, it's, but it's
my, I mean, uh, Microsoft,
the surface is giving me not windows.
The surface is giving me
this weird boot error.
And you're like, this is the re and the
reason I say nine weeks, this is right.
This is a calculated number by me.
IT knowledge right here.
This is a local knowledge of the scene.
It is long enough because the
goal of the surface is, is,
is to behave properly long enough
to lull you into thinking
that it is, that it works.
And then it will rug pull
you at the, and you're,
you're going to wake up one
day and be like, Oh, Oh no.
Oh, Oh wait.
You go to bed feeling great.
And you wake up being in a panic.
Well, here's the good news.
I have another machine.
And I've got a Dell and that's
going to be the production machine.
Um, and you know, cause I have a
couple of these gels laying around.
These are, these are great little
machines, little, little box.
Um, a buddy of mine works
for an oil rig company.
And so they have to replace them every
like 18 months at some, I don't know.
So he just takes them, sends them to me.
No, you get cast offs.
Those are good.
Yeah.
Cast offs are fantastic.
Uh, but I'm, I'm just so blown away
that I was able to get it to work.
This has been a dream for how long
have I been complaining about this?
Oh, 15 years.
Minimum.
Maybe 20.
I don't know.
A long time.
And so in general, you know,
just using Omarchi has been kind
of a cool experience, which is,
you know, so this Arch Linux, um, and
out of the box, it just like all Linux,
um, uh, what is it called?
Uh, builds now.
What's the term people use?
Distro.
Yeah.
That was, well, there you go.
Was it not the computer?
It was the internet.
I have no idea.
I, I, I, everything froze.
I was, everything froze.
I mean, literally, the surface may
have already bit you in the ass.
You meant to say nine
minutes, not nine weeks.
Yeah.
Revenge of the surface.
This, this, I'm, I'm not kidding though.
I got to stop laughing.
I'm not kidding though.
This dock situation, this is
not, this is not sustainable.
This is not going to work.
What's wrong with a dock, man?
Docks are, docks rock.
Dock, dock, this, Thunderbolt
docks are an absolute disaster.
It's not, it's not a Thunderbolt.
It's a, it's a USB-C.
It's, it's Thunderbolt over USB-C.
Oh, that's even better.
That's the problem.
That sounds hot right there.
Let me see.
It's, it, what, when Thunderbolt docks.
When Thunderbolt docks came on the,
came on the scene a few years ago,
I don't know, probably
seven years ago now.
If it was Thunderbolt 3, then it was
Thunderbolt 4, which is what everything is now.
These things are, they are a travesty.
Every single day at the office.
Oh, you got something.
Every day.
It's a dock problem.
A, a, a, a monitor starts blinking,
the internet, the, the network,
the land connection drops.
The, and every single time rebooting
the dock fixes the whole thing.
These things, they got
the latest firmware.
But hold on.
Everything's up to date.
This dock, this is a, it's not even
a, this is a non-powered dongle.
It's not even a dock.
It's just a dongle.
It's, okay.
You said dock.
I thought you meant like a docking
station, like a powered docking station.
No, no, no, no.
This is literally just a one,
two, three, four, four, six,
six port USB expando unit.
Okay.
You got like a, it's kind
of like a port replicator.
Yeah.
That's what it is.
And it's, it's getting power from
the USB-C because it has power.
Yeah.
It's still, and what's all feeding off?
What, what is feeding off this dongle?
Uh, two Rodecaster interfaces, SSD, SSD
hard drive, keyboard, and wireless mouse.
Oh my God.
You have got to get off
this thing immediately.
Off.
You, I, I cannot allow you to go
to production with this machine.
Okay.
But I figured this would be
the place to test and network.
Is network on there too?
Uh, no, no, no, it's just wifi.
I'm just on the wifi.
Okay.
Which is, this dongle thing is
not, is not a good situation.
No one else complains
about my dongle, Dave.
Well, they haven't seen it like I have.
But I, I, once this is all done, I
actually, just before we started,
I noticed a bug in the, in my beautiful
play out system, in my cart wall.
Um, so the first cart that's loaded
plays on the correct interface,
but then the other ones
play on the wrong interface.
So I didn't replicate, I replicated
the player, but forgot to, I guess,
replicate the, uh, the
correct, or make sure it
has the correct port.
Time to whip out Gemini.
It's all been done with Gemini.
That's amazing.
And that really is amazing.
Uh, but I have a repo and,
and, you know, so once,
once I've fixed some of these bugs
and also the, um, so the real
trick, I got to thank this guy.
Hold on a second.
Like one week ago, as I'm, as I'm, as
I'm trying to figure out, cause I,
I have the instructions
like, okay, I understand I can
map these, uh, USB channels.
I can map them, uh, using,
um, uh, the wire stuff.
What is it called again?
I forgot the name.
So I, so I realized I can do
this and then, okay, so I'm,
I'm looking and this
is what's interesting.
So I'm using Gemini.
I'm like, okay, uh, find
for me, um, you know,
something that explains how to do this.
And so the first time around it finds,
it finds, you know, all these different,
uh, instructions and so I'm following
these instructions and then I'm like, ah,
I'm a little frustrated.
So I come back after dinner.
I said, okay, where is that?
Uh, where's those instructions again?
Oh, here's a repo from Jordan Milner,
roadcaster dash pro to dash pipe wire.
I'm like, no way.
And he'd literally, uh,
put this up a week ago.
Now, two weeks.
Oh, so it was very recent.
Yeah.
I'm like, well, thank you.
Thank you very much, bro.
Some pipe wire genius just, just
had to stick something out there.
And he did.
I'm so happy.
I'm so thankful.
Uh, of course, you know, I
need to fix some bugs here.
Some, some post that repo.
Cause I mean, I've got the
duo and, uh, I would like to,
I would like to pipe wire it.
In fact, I forked it.
I forked it for everybody.
There you go.
Oh, of course.
Oh, good, good, good.
I've been learning.
Yeah.
You're, you're using GitHub.
I'm learning.
So pipe wire plumber.
Okay.
Nice.
Pipe wire plumber.
But, um, just in general, um,
Linux is a great experience.
It really is.
The interface is so snappy.
Now the tiling manager took
a little bit to get used to,
but once you're kind of in it,
it's like, I don't think
I want to go back.
I really enjoy the, the
automatic, you can float windows.
That's obviously how I've done the play
out system, but having everything,
uh, snap to tile.
I kind of like it.
Like open up a new, uh, terminal window.
It finds a place, you
know, it's right there.
One click you can, you can, uh, embiggen
it and the other ones go smaller.
It's, it's a different way of working
with, with, uh, uh, with a window manager,
but I kind of dig it.
How I see, you know,
I've used the tiling window manager
a couple of times in the past.
And, and I, I do love, I
do love the keyboards,
like the keyboard master aspect of it.
Yeah.
I'm, I'm sort of a window fidgeter though.
I, I'm just the whole, like the entire
show and, and all, all day long.
I'm just, I'm just tweaking window
positions and moving things around.
And like, it's almost a,
what would you call it?
Like a nervous habit that I have where
I'm just like, I'm like, okay, this,
this window's not, there's a
little bit of a little bit more
space on the left than there
is down on the bottom.
No, no, it's OCD.
I have the exact same thing.
So now when you fidget the window, it,
it rearranges everything along with it.
So like, okay, I got my email open,
Obsidian open and a browser open.
And they're now three, um, vertical tiles.
And so, you know, I just hit the super
key, right click on the mouse, drag it,
the other ones shrink automatically.
I can move it back.
I can move it up.
I can reposition them.
You might actually like this
cause I'm the same way.
I'm like, everything has
to be exactly in the
right spot with the same amount of space
between the window above it and
the wind and the window I'm in.
I completely agree.
Yeah.
It's, I wish I wasn't that way.
I wish I, cause I, I
watched my wife use like
a Mac book and I can't
even look at the screen.
I'm like, I can't look at this.
It's, you know, there's stuff
overlapping stuff everywhere else.
There's like half of a word processor
window hanging off the screen.
Is she still typing into it?
I'm like, Oh no, oh no, oh no.
That's horrible.
Jesus comes soon.
So wrong.
This is not right.
I just, yeah, I can't handle it.
So I'm this, yeah, I'm going to
give this a shot cause you know,
this machine I'm podcasting
on, I mean, this is what year three
of, of podcasting on this Linux box.
And of course I don't have
the needs that you do.
I mean, you're running
master, you know, you know,
master command over there, but it works.
I mean, it, it's fine.
I get, I don't, I've not replaced it.
Um, I tried to replace it one
week and with windows 11,
this is like two years ago and hated it.
And because of it, but,
but it was nice to be able to use
all the audio interfaces on the
roadcaster for that one week.
So if I've got the pipe wire thing,
that just makes life even better.
Yeah.
I'm good.
But my big thing is I was
just so sick and tired.
I'm still on windows 10 for,
for my production machine.
We know, we know all the doomsday
talk, fine, whatever, you know,
it won't shut up about
needing to move to 11.
It just, you know, they just
change things willy nilly.
And in general, the
applications that I really
need and I really want
to use the open source
applications are kind of really good.
And all the other stuff
I'm paying for stuff.
I'm paying for video editing software.
I'm paying for a screen recording
software and you can just find all this.
And it's, I gotta tell
you, it's pretty decent.
And I've looked at all this
throughout the past 20 years.
Uh, and for the first time,
like, okay, this is workable.
You know, it's, uh, yeah.
Yeah.
Well, I'll tell you one thing I
like about, I'm checking out.
I'm just digging into
your screenshot here.
One thing I really like about this is the,
is sort of like the
borderless windows, the
chromeless stuff on here.
Yeah.
Because I don't, I'm, I dig that too.
Cause I don't like the humongous,
uh, catch like a window,
the captions at the top of each window.
And so I don't need any of that.
Well, that, that's, that's the whole point
of Omarchie is you don't have any of that
anymore and you can
completely customize it.
If you want rounded corners, which
I don't, I want sharp edges.
Um, if you want everything to
snap exactly next to each other,
or you can have as, you
know, as many pixels as you
want in between the borders.
It's an OCD person's dream.
I mean, it's like, Oh yeah, yeah.
I can configure this.
Oh yeah, baby.
It's good.
One thing I miss about, uh, Fluxbox,
which was kind of built, yeah,
that was built on the, the, the
theme or the scheme of the window
Chrome was kind of a motif or a centric.
And then, uh, but it was a
very thin window manager.
And one thing I miss
about that is you had,
you could double click
the title bar of a window
and it would like window shade
itself up into the title bar.
Oh, that's cute.
Yeah.
And then you could like double
click it again and it would,
and it would drop back down.
I've had the, the Mac had that.
The Mac still has that, doesn't it?
It doesn't still have that
where you can window shade
or maybe there was an extension you could
load back in the day.
I'm thinking.
It must be an extension.
Yeah.
Cause I, I would like that
cause I could, I could,
I could leave things sort of stacked,
but then shade them up.
And then like it was pre,
this was kind of pre workspace
when you didn't have, right.
Once you could do different workspaces
like that, you didn't really need that.
Yeah.
And I would say with, with Omarci,
you need to be using your workspaces,
which is just,
I guess you can, you can alt F2 or something
like that and flip to a different.
So we, um, in Omarci lab, we
speak of the super key, Dave.
Oh, okay.
So we use the super key
and you can do super key.
One, two, three, four, five, six, seven to
switch between workspaces, a super key.
Everything's with the super key.
So you want to launch an app, super
key space bar, um, just type it in.
It's real nice.
It understands PWAs really well.
It lets you create PWAs.
So if, if I want Gemini,
just opens a Gemini window,
no other browsers, browser stuff.
So no, no bar, no nothing.
You're making, you're just
selling this so hard to me.
I am.
And I'm jiving with you so much.
Well, I watched this video.
I'm tempted to go back to, to, to
Linux on my other main machine.
Well, I watched all these videos of these
guys, you know, the guy who built it.
I'm like, wow, this is really cool.
He's not moving his hands
off the keyboard at all.
It's just like, he's just doing
everything with the keyboard.
I'm like, yeah, that's what I want.
I want 90% of my work,
even more if possible.
Just make it all keyboards.
Fantastic.
Now what goes in the, this screenshot,
what this empty middle here,
what goes in the middle?
Oh, my browser window.
I just pulled it out for the screenshot.
Yeah.
So that's my, that's my, my workspace.
So I have a, a freedom controller
outline, which is open right there.
Yeah.
No, it's an alt tab still works, you
know, for people who like alt tab.
That's important sometimes,
you know, if you're saying,
so I want to switch the boostogram
window, you know, I could
do that real quick.
So I'll, but I will, I'll
be, I'll be publishing this.
Are you doing this Sunday?
Is this going to be, so I actually try.
So yesterday, yes, I got up really early.
Tina had to be somewhere.
So we were up at four 30 or four
o'clock and I'm like, okay, it's like,
I'm going to start the production.
And that's when I really realized
that, okay, the play out system,
I feel pretty good about it.
I probably, we'll see if this thing
lasts throughout the entire show.
I've, you know, let's see, we've
been recording for 30 minutes.
So I think after 15
minutes is when it borked.
So let's see if it's a 15
minute timer on something.
It's possible that there's
a 15 minute thing.
I have no idea what happened.
So that's possible.
I wouldn't want to have to go
through that with no agenda,
but I probably won't do it
until two things happen.
One, I have to find an editing workflow.
Because I am so, I make
up 70 clips for one show.
Maybe only play 50 of them, if that,
but at least I have them depending
on how the conversation goes.
And this, my workflow is so fast.
And, and I started yesterday morning, like,
ah, no, this is, I just can't do this.
Nothing, nothing really comes
close to the Hindenburg pro.
This is a, this is a serious.
So let me ask you some questions.
Um, with Hindenburg, how
much of it do you use?
I mean, is it just a very
small subset of functionality?
Yeah.
Okay.
So record here, the main, in fact, I
even for a little bit there, I'm like,
I'll just build one myself.
That's what I was about to say.
Could you vibe code it?
Um, I actually got to the, so the,
the, here's the main functions.
One, just record and record.
Uh, I need to be able to see
how long it's been recording.
So everything has a timer on it.
I need to be able to use a key band, a
key, a keyboard command to set a marker,
um, for a ISO or so, or an edit
or something like that, you know,
just so I can find it easily.
Then for editing, um, it
uses the H, J, K, L keys.
Um, so I can just do, if you do L,
then it grubs forward normal speed.
If you do LK, it scrubs forward at
double speed and progresses in speed.
The longer you hold it.
So bring, you go really fast, gets faster.
Yeah.
H and J is for reverse.
And then to slow it down, which
I sometimes use, you hit the,
use the L key for forward,
hit the shift key and it
goes, that's really slow.
Um, and then just, uh, setting ID
three tags, image and exporting.
That's all I use it for.
And all the other stuff.
You could vibe code this.
You totally could.
Well, it's funny you say that because
I, I started vibe coding it and I,
I got the scrubbing like within like a 30
minutes, I had the scrubbing part working,
but then I'm just thinking like
the waveform, cause the waveform is tough.
Waveform stuff is complicated.
Why?
To make it, um, this is just what I
noticed with, with this thing to make it,
um, really reflect the volume.
First of all, the volume of the clip.
So, you know, you have to make sure it's
doing that properly, uh, zooming in.
There's a, there's a, you know, how
long it takes to build the waveform,
all kinds of factors that come
in a lot of different factors,
but otherwise I just need an in and out.
I don't need to do multi.
I, I do like sometimes if I'm, if
I'm editing a, some kind of thing,
I want to add multiple
tracks and mix it down, but you
can do that in almost everything.
Um, uh, but the, but this, uh, ocean
audio, I think it's customizable.
I just haven't figured it out yet.
Um, and if not, I should be
able to go in and customize it.
That's the beauty of the open source.
Now, one thing, uh,
somebody, uh, who is this?
Alan Marcus Stratt, Reaper.
Have you tried Reaper?
Yes.
Reaper is so much overkill.
Um, but it's, but it's,
but the thing about Reaper and
I've used Reaper for a long time
for, uh, DAW with music stuff and the thing
about Reaper is you're exactly right.
It's overkill, but it
is so customizable that
you can get rid of all
the overkill and pair
it down to just the
thing you exactly want.
That's what I've been
thinking about doing as well.
I loaded Reaper, um, got it to work
and we're like, what are all these,
what is this mixer stuff popping up and you
know, it's just my brain just fried on.
I'm like, I just want to see
a way form back and forth.
Um, yeah, but yeah, the
amount of customization
you can do in Reaper
to the interface and I
mean, it's outrageous how
much you can customize this.
Okay.
You, you, I feel like it's either, yeah,
I feel like it's either Reaper or,
or you're going to need
to vibe code something.
And yeah, I just feel like you
can, because like waveform stuff,
there's got to be tons.
There's got to be so much sample code out
there already to handle stuff like that.
There's got to be, uh,
anyway, welcome to podcast.
This is great.
Well, it'll be my gift to the world, man.
And everybody will be able to, to use it.
And it's, I don't think there's a, no,
I know there's not a single
podcast play out system
like the one I've designed does not exist.
This is going to be out of left
field a little bit, but, um, you,
you may want to ultimately
get a machine that has ECC RAM.
ECC.
Isn't that the, the stuff
that protects, yeah.
That protects if a bit is, uh, is
corrupted, then it automatically correct.
That's, that's what
happened with the airplane.
Yeah.
That's what, that's what happened
with that, uh, Airbus that went down.
The ECC, you get a, yeah, yeah, you get
a stray, um, like I was hearing, um,
Linus Torvald's talk, not that,
not that long ago about, uh, he,
he only uses ECC RAM in
all of his workstations
and you, you, you associate
ECC with servers.
Yeah.
Um, and, but, and if you use that,
but if it's really important
to make sure the integrity
of your memory is solid,
particularly with audio stuff.
Yeah.
And I'm just wondering
about, cause when you're,
when you're talking about like loading
a waveform and that kind of thing, I mean,
you're essentially
building an inmate unit.
You're building a matrix of a
potentially large, you know,
by a large binary matrix in memory.
And if you just get one thing that
just can, gets kind of crashes, yeah,
cocked up in that thing.
I mean, yeah, I just
feel like things would
be a whole lot more stable and
that that's what he was saying.
He was like, he was like,
I've had machines before where I've just
had tons and tons of problems with them.
And I thought it was an
operating system problem.
And then I like switched out
the Ram to something else.
And it was like, everything was
instantly, it was all better.
Huh.
You know, I'm thinking these Dell,
these Dells may have ECC Ram because,
you know, because of the, because
they're on oil rigs, like, like, uh,
or I think it's a seed
drilling rigs actually.
Yeah.
A lot of those, uh, like things
that made for industrial use.
Yeah.
A lot of those do have, cause
they need to be rock solid.
Yeah.
Embedded devices, things like that.
They just have to, you know, cause you,
you can't afford to have
those things make a mistake.
Anyway.
So then I'm also going to be building the,
uh, Quinn dash TTS, uh, model on the,
on the, the new, not this machine, but
on the new machine, that's the, uh,
that's the very cool open source
competitor to 11 labs, which I see, man,
there's so much cool stuff right now.
That's coming out.
What's it called?
Uh, Quinn.
It's from, uh, Alibaba.
I think Q.
Oh, the Quinn, the Quinn audio model.
Yeah.
And it was the other thing.
Um, someone showed me this.
Hold on a second.
Um, there was something else really cool.
It was this thing you download Pinocchio,
Pinocchio, Pinocchio, Pinocchio.co.
Just spelled in the normal way.
No.
P I N O K I O dot C O.
And it's basically you load it
and you're running a cloud.
So it's called the one
click local host cloud.
And it makes it really easy because they
have all these pre compiled, um, uh,
things such as Quinn, Quinn three TTS.
So, you know, compiling that is,
that was an interesting little,
I'd started to do it and
like, okay, now this is, this is too much.
Um, but they've got a lot.
If you look at, so it's Pinocchio.co.
They've got, uh, Quinn three TTS.
They've got song generation studio, vibe
voice, real time, ultimate TTS studio.
I mean, there's a lot of stuff here.
I wonder that the, the Quinn TTS
model doesn't look like it's, uh,
is that not an open model?
Yeah, it is.
Cause it's not on a llama.
No, it's not on llama.
No, I know.
Uh, but it's, yeah, it's open.
Maybe they just, it just got
released like a week or two ago.
So maybe they just haven't put it in yet.
Um, but there's a lot of
stuff that you can load
with this and that's just much easier.
Uh, and they've got really light versions
of it that you can run, you know,
on a surface pro six.
Yeah.
So with that in mind, I think,
uh, I think AI has done me well.
I have no idea how they, how
they make money off of me.
They, they don't, they, this, this whole
thing is like the part, I have two,
uh, open web UI servers, um, that
I kind of constantly fiddle with.
And honestly, some of it is just the,
the fear that this whole
thing is going to blow up.
And I just want to keep, you
want to have some local stuff.
Yeah.
I just want to keep some local
stuff around because I, I did it.
This thing is a financial
disaster waiting to happen.
I mean, you saw, you saw what
happened to Microsoft, I guess.
It was amazing.
You had, um, uh, uh, meta Facebook
investing $75 billion into AI stuff.
They pop up 6% and Microsoft dropped 6%
and they're only investing $30 billion.
It's like, because they can't
make it, they can't make it work.
Yeah, exactly.
Nobody wants their AI stuff.
Nobody.
They can't sell it.
Yeah.
I mean, like at least, at least somebody
like Anthropic has a product that,
that is, that has buzz and people want, but
the, you know, and, and they're selling,
there's, there's quite a, I mean,
there's a lot of people that
are paying them 200
bucks a month for this,
you know, for the cloud
code stuff, but Microsoft,
they can't make a dime on this stuff.
Yeah.
You're not, you're not deploying any of
that at the, at the day job, are you?
Nobody is.
I mean, like they, they want to, they,
they will not tell anybody
corporate adoption numbers.
They just want, I mean,
nobody wants their $30,
$35 a month add on for
365 for the AI stuff.
It's just like for co-pilot
and all these things,
they're going to go somewhere else
and get just a better product.
Is it really that the product is no good
or is it, is it just that it doesn't,
it's in the wrong place?
It, nobody, they did the tip, this
is the typical Microsoft way.
They got a name for something
and they deployed it
everywhere and called
it all the same thing.
So everything is co-pilot and
nobody knows what any of it is.
You know, you, you open
up edge and you have
a co-pilot button in
your edge browser, but
that's not the same co-pilot as what
you get if you pay for 365 co-pilot,
which also gives you a co-pilot button in
your app, but it's a different button.
And now they put a co-pilot
button even on the
regular non-paid
subscription 365 apps, but
that's not the same co-pilot button,
but they all look the same
and they all do something
different and half the
time they don't work.
And the minute you hit that
button, if you're non-paying,
the first thing it says is, oh,
you got to have cloud, man.
If you don't have the cloud,
we can't do it for you.
Got to be on the cloud.
Like, no, cancel.
It's the Microsoft way.
They just don't, they,
they, they always do this.
They try to call everything windows or
everything office or everything Microsoft.
And it's just a confusing mess.
And yeah, I think, I think
the problem with the
invest when the investor
stuff and the reason
they tank so hard is,
is that they're spending $30 billion
a quarter on AI build out and they
can't sell any AI.
Right.
Whereas, whereas, whereas Meta says, well,
we're using AI to increase
our ad revenue when they
had better admin revenue.
And then you look over here
and Apple is doing nothing
with AI and they're making $40 billion
in profit a quarter.
Well, they have, there's
a distinct chance they're
going to screw everything
up because they, wow.
So Microsoft is down again, 3% today.
They're going to, and gold is down 30%.
Holy crap.
What just happened?
Whoa, what is gold under $5,000?
Wait, silver drops 30%.
Oh man.
Gold tumbles 10.
What was I going to say?
I really think that Apple,
because, you know, they,
they want to have Siri become like your
chat bot, which I think
by itself is dumb because
people are already invested
in their chat bots.
You know, they've already customized it.
And, you know, they, with the, with the
attitude and the, um, uh, what is it?
The personality that they want it to be.
It's like, ah, okay, fine.
Um, so Siri is going to have to
be something kind of uniform.
I don't think they'll have
it customizable and it's,
it's going to make mistakes and people
will not accept that.
They don't accept the
mistakes from Apple products.
Yeah.
I mean, they, I don't know
why they're even bothering.
Honestly, they made more money from, uh,
they made something like
$80 billion in revenue
from just the iPhone.
Yeah.
I mean, just that one
device, like why even, why,
why even bother with all
the rest of the stuff?
I mean, just do one thing and do it well.
Get rid of your Macs.
Yeah.
Siri has, Siri has blown
chunks for how many years now?
Forever.
And it's not, it has never stopped a
single person from buying an iPhone.
Right.
Yeah.
Well, it's the promise, I guess.
The, the, the, the underwhelming delivery,
delivery on the promise
is what the problem is.
Yeah.
So did I read that you spent eight bucks
on some app or something that, that,
that deletes the advertisements and add,
uh, and, and host red ads in your podcasts?
Okay.
So I, I gave my, I gave my, you know,
spiel about my twit
subscription to security now
and windows weekly and how you want,
you want to, you want to pay for it,
not get the ads and,
but still get chapters.
I want chapters.
Yes.
Yeah.
And so I was like, okay, I'm interested
in this on device ad skipping technology.
Let's, let's, uh, I'm already
a subscriber to twit.
So I downloaded, I downloaded this
app, paid the eight bucks to,
for the in-app purchase
to upgrade to ad skipping.
This app that I tried out was called
ear, ear say, ear say, ear say, ear say.
Okay.
Not familiar with this product.
That was brand new.
And so, um, I paid the eight bucks,
subscribed to windows weekly
and a security now the regular
feed, not my private, uh,
subscription, uh, member feed.
And I'm like, okay, well, this is fine.
Cause I'm, I'm paying
for the, I'm subscribed.
I'm a subscriber.
I don't feel bad or guilty about this.
I'm going to just use these as tests.
It's horrible.
It's this, this, I'm look, I don't,
I'm not going to throw podcast app,
any podcast app developer
anywhere under the bus.
No, it's just not, it's a hard job.
It's a hard thing.
It's very difficult to make a good
app and it takes a long time.
Yes.
Well, all I'm going to say is
this app has real struggles.
Um, and hold on, hold
on, Dave, hold on me.
There goes the surface.
Hold on, hold on.
The whole thing froze up.
Come back, please.
Oh no.
Right.
I'm going to pause.
Did it come back?
Fundamentally.
Okay.
Hold on.
Hold on, Dave.
When you go in there, it
does like a, Dave, hold on.
Oh, are we, no, it's, uh,
are we Linuxing again?
Oh yeah.
No, you've been frozen
for about two minutes.
Hold on.
Oh no.
Yeah.
Come on.
It's, it's trying to come back to life.
It's coming back.
It's trying to come back.
Can you, can you hear me?
I can hear you a little bit.
Hold on.
Uh, okay.
All right.
Are you there?
Oh no, you went away.
Reconnect.
Probably the worst I've ever seen it.
Okay.
Come on.
You back?
Yeah.
I've been here the whole time.
Holy moly.
That was, that was amazing.
The whole system froze.
Oh yeah.
No, it was good.
So go back and tell me
about the, uh, I think I,
I think you dropped out
when you were telling
me about what the system does.
What's it called again?
Oh, earsay.
Yeah.
Earsay.
Let's pick it up from earsay.
I don't, I said so much.
I don't even remember what I said.
I'm so sorry.
I, I, I know why it
happened because I switched
to another desktop to
do something while you
were talking and that, that screwed it up.
So I'm not going to touch it.
This, this, I'm, I'm telling
you it's the surface.
I'm, I'm, you got to
get rid of that thing.
Uh, anyway.
So yeah, the, the, I don't want to,
I don't want to throw in the
podcast app under the bus.
Yeah.
That's why I lost you.
No, no throwing under the bus.
Yes.
No.
Writing a podcast app is
hard, but this, this podcast.
The podcast app has some
critical flaws in it, which,
in which make it completely
really unusable.
It won't download podcasts properly.
Okay.
That's, that's a problem.
Yeah.
That's a real problem.
Wait a minute.
How does it work?
Does it, does it download?
Does it do it on the fly?
Is it doing on a transcript?
How does it detect ads and remove them?
What, what is, do you
know what the process is?
Supposedly it's loading
some sort of on device
model and then analyzing the audio file.
Maybe it's running a transcript first.
I would assume that's what it's doing.
It's doing its own transcript and
then trying to use, um, you know,
the model to sort of
tease out what is a, um, what, what's,
what's a host read ad, some kind of ad read.
And then, but the problem is it takes, it,
it won't download podcasts hardly at all.
And then it takes a long time.
Hold on, stop.
What do you mean hardly at all?
Does it, is it, does it say it's
downloading, but it doesn't?
Or what does that mean?
Qualify?
Okay.
So I'm, so I hope I'm looking
at the app right now.
So, um, I've got, I've only
got two podcasts in here, uh,
windows weekly and security now.
And let me go windows weekly.
It says that it's downloaded,
but if I go to the queue that shows my
downloaded podcasts, it's not there.
Okay.
That's a problem.
But if, but if I, if I do mark, if I,
but if I do any functions
at the top of the queue,
it asks me if I want to mark this episode
as red, but so it's like, I, it's like,
I can't see it, but it's actually
there, but will it play?
It plays.
I can get it to, I can get it to play.
But when the first time you play the
episode, it, it does this thing.
It's like, it makes a little, it makes a
little jingle for a few, for like maybe, I
don't know, like 30 seconds or a minute.
And then, and when it finishes
beat bopping, then it comes with,
then it'll start playing the episode.
And I think that it was that, that's
like, it's, it's spending that time,
like analyzing the, the, the thing.
It's giving you, it's giving you robot sounds
like I'm working, I'm doing something.
Yeah, yeah, yeah, exactly.
Yeah.
Boop, boop, boop, boop, boop, boop.
And so then it gives you a, um, like
an audio, like a, your timeline,
your slider, you know,
to jump back and forth.
And there's red sections in the
slider, which it thinks are audio,
which it thinks are ads.
Problem is it gets to the
ad and plays like maybe
20% of the ad skips about 40% through
the middle of the ad and then plays like
the remaining percent and then plays.
So it's not really skipping the whole ad.
It's just skipping like
sort of like a half the ad.
And so it's, it's very, and,
and then the other problem is
it skips things that aren't
ads because it thinks they're
ads, but they're not.
Like just the middle, like
kind of like my Linux system.
It just, uh, cuts something out
in the middle, just willy nilly,
whatever it feels like.
It just decides when Dave is
necessary and when he's not.
Got it.
Yes.
And so the, like if you, for instance,
you were sitting there
giving me the rundown of the
way that your new system works.
You're telling me about all of its features
and what you're, what you're doing.
It may think that that's
an ad because you're
talking about features and things like you
would be talking about a product.
Right.
And so one, one of the things like in,
in security, latest security now, um,
Steve Gibson is talking
about this AI model from this
particular company and he's giving,
he just ran down what they
say this model does.
And it was sort of like a lot of ad speak.
We'll just skip right over what
he's just like, it blew out like,
like six minutes of what he was saying.
I'm like, Whoa, Whoa, it's
just not a great product.
And so I don't know if it,
if that's indicative of this thing
being vibe coded by somebody who
doesn't know really how to write apps.
I don't know, but we're seeing a
proliferation now of sort of sort of,
of these things.
And, and some of them
are clearly vibe coded.
Like there was a new
platform this week for
analytics that John Spurlock posted about.
And that's, it says right in the thing
that this thing was built with cloud code.
So I think there's a, there's a
lot of people pushing, you know,
they're selling things now
new services and that kind
of thing that are vibe
coded that just may not fully understand
what they've built and how
it works and how to fix it.
But you know, but it is, but
this is, this is a real thing.
This, this is going to be, this
is going to be the future.
And I don't think anybody
really is prepared for
what that's going to mean for things like
DAI because that stuff,
this is just the rough first attempt
at doing something like this.
And we know the way these things
go, it's just going to get better.
It's all going to get,
we just need more power.
If only we had more power, we need more
data centers and power data centers.
We've read this.
We, we have read this story
before the story of what's
happening in podcasting with AI right now
is the story of the web
and free written content.
First, you get the ad blockers.
Yeah.
You know, then you get, then
you get the anti ad blockers.
Yeah.
And none of that works.
And eventually these, the,
the sites start putting their
written content behind paywall.
And that's, what's going to happen here.
You're going to have, at some
point, once this ad skipping,
audio ad skipping technology
just becomes sort of more mainstream
and, and more reliable and where,
and people begin to adopt it in mass the
way that they've adopted ad blockers.
Once that happens.
It's over.
You're just, you're just going to
see people go behind a paywall.
Right.
Which is, which is, is, is
never made sense to me.
Me and from a monetary
standpoint, you build it up,
you get your audience and then you take
them behind the paywall.
You're very vulnerable when you do
that because, you know, I mean,
we just as an example, no
agenda, which is PayPal has
always been the main, uh,
the main value for value income stream.
And when we had the PayPal apocalypse,
if you remember when everyone
got really pissed off
at PayPal, what were they mad about?
I forgot what that was.
Because PayPal said it had
something to do with censorship.
Oh yeah, that's right.
Yeah.
If you were doing certain,
what was it again?
I'm sorry.
I didn't mean to interrupt you.
It's like certain people
you could donate to
if they determined that
it was bad and that
they could also like penalize you,
like take some of your money
away or something like that.
Right.
So everybody on mass went, yeah,
screw those guys and canceled
all of their recurring payments,
which is, it's probably 15
to 20% of our income is
people just set and forget
at five or $11 or $12.
It's the same with podcasting 2.0.
Um, and also end of the year, um,
although some financial services
are pretty interesting.
They just somehow put your new
credit card in when it expires.
I've seen that amazing how that works.
Um, yeah, but we have to
remind people like go
check because it's because they won't tell
you, you know, PayPal
doesn't tell you, oh,
we canceled this because your
card expired or whatever.
Um, or you may not have seen the email.
Um, so, you know, it's
just like the stream,
the streaming video guys
at a certain point,
people just start cutting back.
They make choices.
We've talked about this.
And then, you know, they're
going to look and say, well,
I got 150 bucks worth of subscriptions
every, uh, every month.
Like I'm going to cut something here.
And so, you know, I think it's impossible
to build something up that is,
you know, the whole freemium model.
I've never believed in that.
I think it's complete horse crap.
Like, you know, I'm giving
you this content here,
but they're really good
stuff you got to pay for.
I'm thinking, no, no, no, no.
And the relevance, just
the relevance of people
being able to hear what you have to say or
pass it on to somebody, you know,
then they're jumping through
hoops and trying to figure it
out and, uh, and then making copies.
And, you know, then there's
like, uh, like Rogan,
how many bogus Rogan feeds do we have
when he was Spotify exclusive?
They were popping up every single day.
Yeah.
You know, so it, it just, it's just,
the model is kind of flawed, but yeah,
if you get 250,000
people and you say,
okay, subscription now,
and you're able to keep
50,000, maybe more.
Okay.
That's a, that's a good payday, but it's,
it's a very, very dangerous situation.
Doesn't take much.
One de-platforming of a financial
institution or whatever, and you're done.
You're just done.
Yeah.
I don't think, I think this is a
bad, this is a bad thing for people,
for just podcasting in general.
I mean, we, we just know, we just know
how this ends and they can't, the, the,
the podcasters that are, that are,
that are steeped in the advertising
lingo and the advertising thought process.
So now when you fidget, right click on the
mouse, drag it, cause I'm the same way.
I'm like, everything has to be.
And they think the only
nervous habit is paywall.
Yeah.
That's like their own.
Horrible.
Jesus comes in.
So wrong.
They never think about it.
All day long.
I'm just for donate.
I can just add value for
value for donations.
And I think that's going to, there's
going to, you're going to see,
I just feel like over
the next 20, 2026, but by the end
of this year, this is January,
by the end of this year,
I think that's going to be the story,
but that's all going value for value.
You mean?
No, it's all going to,
you're going to see,
we're going to look back
a few years from now
and see that 2026 was the year
that there was a pivot from, um,
from advertising based
podcasting to paywall based podcasting
subscription, subscription only podcasting.
And it's going to be because
of this ad blocking stuff.
It's going to, by the end of
the year, there's going to be,
there's going to be a lot
more of this happening.
And the, the tradition, the normal
podcast app developers, people, you know,
people like pocket casts and Marco and,
um, Apple podcasts and these, they don't,
they don't want to do this because a
lot of them like, like Marco, I mean,
he's got his own show that's advertising
supported, you know, he's, I mean,
this is like, that would be like,
you know, biting the hand
that feeds you, so to speak,
or there's probably a
better metaphor for that.
And there's going to be a lot of, and
like Frank, Franco Solerio, he, you know,
he's a podcaster and has run a
podcast for many, many years.
I mean, I don't know how long, but I
mean, he's a podcaster going way back.
He has a very frequent show that he,
that he's run with lots of episodes.
People who have been around in the
podcasting world for a really,
really long time, they're
not going to want to do this,
but you're going to see these other apps
like this one pop up that will do it.
They don't care.
And people will start moving to these,
to these apps because it's irresistible.
Yeah.
And I just feel like that,
I feel like we're going to look
back in 2026 is going to be
this sort of like line in the sand moment.
I mean, truly advertise, you know, I
learned a new acronym yesterday from Rocky.
We text from time to time, the rock
line, talking on the rock line.
And, uh, she said, well,
you know, fast, like fast,
what's fast F-A-S-T all, all uppercase.
Oh, free ads, ad supported television.
And she says that these things
are cropping up everywhere.
People are, are propping up live
video streams and, you know,
they're getting cheap old shows
and they're jamming.
It's like, you know, Pluto, uh, Tubi,
uh, all these types of outfits.
Because really it's only in a
linear format that it really works.
In a linear real-time format, that's
when you can, can drop in ads.
Everything else is susceptible
to the fast forward button,
to the skip ahead 60 seconds, you know,
the whole TiVo thing.
Um, it's, and also it's the
only way to create scarcity.
If there's only X amount of, of, um,
of ad slots in a 60 minute hour,
then you can create scarcity.
So we're in this, this middle, I mean,
man, we've been seeing it with, uh,
Salem radio network
who are, you know, one of the,
I'd say one of the biggest Christian
broadcasters, ad supported.
They already sold off
all their music stations
because that was just
too expensive, I guess.
But now they're, they're dropping
expensive hosts left and right.
You know, Eric Metaxas,
they are Dinesh D'Souza.
I mean, why?
Because they either have to run 15
minutes or 20 minutes of ads an hour,
or they have to cut costs somewhere.
The whole thing.
It's, you know, the whole, the
whole, I think you said it best,
you know, radio isn't broken.
The, the business of radio is broken.
And of all media, all linear
media advertising worked
and will there always be
something that works?
Yeah, of course.
But just look at the, at, um, at
banner ads, you know, that's,
that's pennies now pennies.
If that, you, you know, you,
you talked about this a long
time ago about how the, uh, the
scarcity of linear media and,
and print media created,
made it possible for advertising to work.
And then when it went to the web,
it broke that because now you have
unlimited, there's no more scarcity.
You just hit the refresh button over and
over and over and you have more ad space.
Yeah.
You know, you talked about that.
The thing about podcasts, well, excuse me,
the thing about the
internet giants that have
made advertising work,
people like Facebook and Google is
they created artificial scarcity.
Yes.
The reason they're successful
at it is they created
artificial scarcity through the, through
owning the entire pipeline.
There wasn't, you couldn't,
you couldn't go anywhere.
I mean, that's, that's
clearly come out in court
documents and then the end discovery at
this point is that they own,
they own the entire market all the way
from the bidding down to the display.
They own every link in the chain.
So you really, what they did was they,
they created a monopoly
over the entire pipeline so
that they invented artificial
scarcity where there was not any.
Right.
And, but that's not something that, that's
not something that podcasting can do.
I mean, DAI, if you have a host read
ad, yes, that is, that is scarcity.
But if, but with DA, with
dynamic ad insertion,
it's just the web problem
over and over and over.
You have unlimited, you have
unlimited, unlimited inventory.
Exactly.
And, and with host read ads, which I
do think is the only way to do it,
you need a large audience
to make any kind of
sustaining money off of that.
That's, that's where the problem comes in.
And as soon as, as soon as some
of these things get popular, the,
the advertisers are going to
get very skeptical of the numbers.
Well, there's, there's, there's, there's
the elephant in the room is the, uh, huh?
Like, uh, how, what are you measuring?
Huh?
Does someone actually listen?
Yeah.
That's why I love value for value works.
I mean, it's a rollercoaster
economy, bad, less value comes in.
It's like, I, I hurt the same with, as
our, as our listeners, our producers,
I hurt right along with them, but
it's amazing how, um, you know,
I don't even know how many people listen
to our show, but I don't, I, I
just don't look, I don't care.
Um, it's amazing to see how, you know,
you'll have like very few people donating.
And then on that very day,
someone comes in with like
$3,333 and 33 cents, like what?
And then you can sit there and say, cause
I've, for 18 years, we're like, well,
we would have
been toast if this guy hadn't, hadn't
jumped in, but it's always like that.
For some reason, it just works that way.
If you remind people, you tell people
how it works and you thank them.
That is, that's critical.
This, I mean, this show is a,
just a smaller version of that.
I mean, we, you know, we, cause
we, we have the same thing.
A lot of, yeah, a lot
of people come in, uh,
somebody came in today at the last second,
you know, with a, with a good donation.
So like we, yeah, it's, it's, I, I,
obviously we're a smaller show
in magnitude, smaller show
than no agenda, but it's the,
I have the same feeling about
it on a week to week basis.
And it's really, it's kind of, it's
really cool, you know, it is, well,
we couldn't live off of this, you
know, but that's not the point.
And there we go.
And that's it.
What are you really podcasting for?
Everybody wants to make money.
Everybody's all about making money.
Why would I waste my time doing this?
And I look at the
influencers cooking shows.
I put more cheese on it.
No, this, look at the cheese.
It looks like Tina, the
other day, she's like,
I'm going to make cottage
cheese pizza crust.
I'm like, did you get
this off of Instagram?
She said, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Okay.
She pulls it out of the oven.
She says, hmm, that's not now how it
looked on that person's Instagram.
Oh man.
I went to the movies with my son last night
and he was like, he was like, I made,
he was like, I made the mistake.
He said, I made the mistake of,
of his came to a video came through
his timeline about something
with the Minnesota protester stuff.
And so he's like, I made the
mistake of, of clicking,
of tapping on it to watch that video.
And he said, now my entire timeline is
just nothing but that all the time.
And he's like, he's like, I just
deleted Instagram off my phone.
Yeah.
No, it's like, I can't handle it.
That's the same with Tik TOK.
And, and you know, the,
everyone's kind of figured out the
algorithm is just, you want this.
We're going to give you a
whole bunch of that until
you click three times on something else.
And then when you get a
whole bunch of that, this,
I don't see much sophistication anymore
because, you know, because work related.
Okay.
I'm looking at these videos of
Minneapolis and then it decides, well,
you probably want more
people killing each other.
So here's some other cool videos to watch.
Like, no, no, I'm not really, I'm
not really, not really into that.
You know, more Russian body cam footage.
Yeah.
No, I don't get those.
I get the, the sovereign citizens.
Oh, you click on that once, you know,
the sovereign, like, um, I'm traveling,
but your tag is expired and you
see your license registration.
I'm traveling.
And, uh, uh, do you have a
proof that I did something?
And like, uh, and they wind
up breaking their window,
dragging them out, arresting them.
Uh, and that's a good day.
That's a good day.
So you watch one or two of those
and the timeline is just stacks.
Anyway, it's the, on the adjacent to that,
to this advertising or
ad skipping stuff, you
know, what I, what I was talking about last
week was an, you know, like an API, some
kind of API to be able to,
to feed bits of like amendments
to a feed back to yourself.
That was the, and so I actually, I, uh,
spent a little bit of time this week,
uh, just running a local, like
testing my local LLM to see how
far I could get with a little bit of this.
And it just, it hit me though.
You don't, if we just had a spec for this,
I know, I know you're probably like,
come on, get Dave, let it go.
No, I listen.
When you're on something,
I listened to you.
I've learned.
It's good to listen.
The, we don't need an API.
That's overkill.
What, all we need is just some XML.
So like, if I, if I want to add,
if I want to append or amend
some content to a feed in
some way, I should just be able
to say, Oh, here's some other,
here's some extra XML over here.
And I want you to just pull that XML
into this feed at this location,
almost like an inclusion of an OPML file.
Right.
So, but I think what I'm saying, if we,
if we just had a spec
that shows you that says
how to address an amend,
an amended XML document.
So, I mean, the problem is
this is hard to describe.
So what I'm saying, so no,
let's say no agenda, um,
the feed has somebody's a subscriber and
they're like, you know what?
I wish no agenda.
I wish the feed had this one
little bit of extra content in it.
Now, maybe not a great,
maybe not a great example because your
feed is already very feature complete.
Maybe there's this one thing missing
that they wish that it had in it.
Well, Hey, maybe it's
even their own images.
Maybe they want their own podcast
artwork, item level podcast artwork.
Um, there should be a way to tell
an app anytime you download, uh,
anytime you find a new, uh,
anytime you parse a feed,
also go out to this location and
check if there's some extra XML
out here that you should then just
merge into this feed at this location.
And that way it's, it's a
way for a user to customize
an existing feed to their own liking.
Well, let's put it all together.
Let's put the, everything we've
been talking about together.
Um, considering that, especially
with this Pinocchio outfit, it's,
it's becoming, people
are seeing, and this is
something Claude bot.
Have you heard of that?
C-L-A-W-D?
Claude?
Yeah.
Didn't it, wasn't there some kind of
data breach or something with them?
No, I don't think so.
Maybe it's an open source project and you,
you download it and then
you connect it to your
favorite AI and the Claude
bot then does stuff for you.
So you can interact with
it through email or
through a telegram or
WhatsApp and you say,
Hey, do this for me.
It's kind of a remote, but it,
you can give it tasks to do.
So it's like an agent that's
sitting on top of your favorite AI,
but these things are becoming
increasingly easier for
someone to install.
Yeah.
This, this past weekend, the tech world
watched in real time as Claude bot,
an open source personal AI
assistant went from niche developer
tool to viral phenomenon
to a security case
study in about 72 hours.
Oh, what happened?
Security researchers found
over a thousand exposed
servers demonstrating
prompt injection attacks.
It extracted credentials in minutes.
Okay.
Well, we have some, uh, some
birthing pains, obviously, but,
but let's just consider for a second
that, um, it's going to be easier
for people to grab that old,
that old piece of crap machine
they got somewhere that
everyone has an upgrade
somewhere or on the
machine you're working on.
If you want download something, I can
see a world where you have a, um,
a proxy and the proxy
is just some LLM, some logic that
sits there and does all this for you.
And then you subscribe to your own private
feeds from your own private system.
I have a real hard time seeing anyone
building this for, for profits, uh,
cause just lawsuit waiting to happen.
You know, it's just, you know, so let's,
let's forget about the
monetary aspect and let's just
think about the cool,
the coolness factor where you should
be able to connect your, your
app to your own middleware and that
middleware, you know, you used to say, okay,
I want to subscribe to this and
says, okay, here's the feed.
And that feed is a customized
feed just for you.
Or maybe it's an API or whatever it is.
It doesn't have to be a feed.
And, and it, it processes, it does the
chapters, it does all this stuff for you,
um, removes ads and, um,
and then you're done.
And then you could share that with your
buddies, you know, like next cloud,
or in fact, it should
be a next cloud plugin, a next cloud app.
I can, this, this will be a future for a
small percent, but it eventually it grows.
I mean, it's just like Linux.
I'm re I'm, I don't know if it's true,
but I'm reading that Linux
desktop is now somewhere
near 18% market share.
It seems high to me.
Yeah.
That seems high to me too.
But even if we're 8%, I mean,
what was, I mean, yeah,
high single digits is a huge deal.
I mean, yeah.
So why, you know, you know, these home
servers, you know, this has been the,
I've been talking about the, well,
you'll have just have a server in your,
this was back in the original days
before podcasting, before podcasting.
I think the, the last
yard essay that I wrote,
which kind of birthed the
enclosure, the enclosure
tag in RSS in 2000, well before we
had the iPod was you'll have a,
every home will come
with a server and the server does stuff.
And what it does is
downloading media for you.
It's queuing it up, getting it ready, make
sure, you know, which is Plex in a way.
And this is what start nine is.
This is what Umbrell is supposed to be.
It's start nine.
I got to tell you that it's a knock on
wood, but it's been rock, rock solid.
You know, it's just, the
stuff is just there.
It's always on.
It's accessible via Tor.
So I don't have to deal with
any networking nonsense.
It just kind of works for me.
So why wouldn't I have all,
I mean, I have Olama on it.
It's slow, but it works.
Yeah.
I feel like, so there's a,
I think there's a reason this is all
jumbled up in my head right now.
And it's got to do with this threat,
this sort of AI threat to the model.
Cause if, if what happens is AI
ad blocking drives podcasters,
popular podcasts out of open
RSS into a subscription
model with private feeds,
then that's going to be a huge hit.
to RSS across the board for podcasting.
And so I feel like the pod,
I feel like the podcast namespace
was a way that we could make
sure that open RSS still complete competed
with closed systems in their feature set.
But I feel like now is a time that we
need to have a way where people can,
what is the LLM AI thing
that's happening right now?
I mean, the real crux of the whole
thing and why it's such a big deal,
at least in the, in
the vibe coding and this kinds of
thing, the tech enthusiasts are,
are on it because it allows
you to build a thing and have a hyper
customized solution to a problem,
just exactly like what you
just built with your Linux podcasting rig.
You can build the thing exactly
the way you want it to be.
And I think that if that's the mindset
of this era that we're currently going
through, then RSS has to be that
also, I mean, and it's
the perfect thing to do.
So we should be able to,
we should be able to construct an open way
that people can create, can, can take an
existing feed and sort of munge it into a
thing that is more of the thing they want.
Okay.
So let me just get one
thing straight with you.
I do not believe that
you can start a podcast
today behind the paywall.
It's just not going to work, you know,
you, unless you're doing premium
content, which I just have never really
seen it work successfully except for
something that's already big.
So how do you get big?
You know, it's like Howard Stern.
Howard Stern was big because he was
syndicated on radio stations
across the country.
And then he said, come with
me behind the paywall,
which was Sirius XM and
two things happened.
A lot of people went behind
the paywall and he became
irrelevant within months.
No one was talking about, so if you're
irrelevant and no one else can talk
about what you're saying or what you're
doing, how do people find out about it?
How do they find,
Oh, I mean, is it, you know, okay, I
guess you can do trial periods and stuff,
but it's, that's, that's not mass media.
Now you're, you're doing
something completely different.
So I always think
people will want to have
podcasts, audio, video,
otherwise that are available, searchable,
findable, uh, through an app or
any kind of app that you use, um,
in order to get any kind of scale.
Yeah.
Go ahead.
I'm sorry.
Well, the index is perfectly
suited for the other side of that,
which is, okay, there's all these features
that I'm not getting from this podcast.
I want to click a button
and get these features.
I think that's, that by the
way, is perfectly valid.
You know, if, if you're accessing it, if
it's free access, then I should be able to,
you know, if I want to
listen at three times speed, which I
detest, but if someone wants to do that,
you know, I can't, I can't stop them.
I don't want to stop them.
Uh, but I think we just have to
take the money out of the equation.
You can't serve two masters.
Yeah.
But I think, I know what you're saying.
I think that what I'm trying,
I'm not really talking about like
things going behind the paywall.
Well, I think what I'm afraid of
is that is, is podcast direct,
when you is searching for a
podcast in a directory
comes an experience that
feels like an app store
where you're searching
through the list and some
are free and some are paid.
And it just looks like
that's not what we have now.
What we have now is
everything is basically open.
You can listen to anything that
you want at any time.
And you just may have to deal with
ads or you can possibly go find some
subscription.
Then you get the ads that
you don't get the ads.
That's what podcasting is.
But if it comes down to where the podcast
ads begin to have to say, well, this one,
you're going to have to pay for it.
Well, this other one, you're
going to have to pay for it.
It's just going to, I think
it's just going to ruin it.
Well, I think that's different.
I mean, you know, there's, there's not
many ways you can do that except
for, you know, Sam Sethi's, um,
what is his secure, secure, secure RSS.
Yeah.
Secure RSS.
You know, maybe, um, people will
beg, steal, do anything they can to
get the content they want for free.
I mean, I've, I have very close friends
who I, uh, excoriate frequently.
Like, oh, I just go get
that movie from tour.
Like, well, you're an asshole.
You're an asshole.
But I pay for my, if someone wants me to
pay for their content, I'll pay for it.
If it's value for value,
I will return value.
You know, if I have to listen
to ads, I'll listen to ads.
I'm not really an ad skipper.
I find the ads kind of
entertaining sometimes.
Um, I see no danger at all
of podcast index or any other, uh,
any other, I mean, Apple may be, um,
in fact, that would be
the mistake they made.
You know, if they said, oh,
well you can't access it.
I don't know how it works.
So you're looking at your, uh,
your podcast app and it says you can't
listen to this unless you subscribe.
Yeah.
I mean, some of them
are subscription only.
Well, good.
Then screw those guys.
I'd rather have a 2 million free
than 5 million of which, uh,
half of those are paid only.
I just want to get ahead of any sort of
worrying trend with a solution to the
problem before the
problem manifests itself.
You know, that's really what I'm like.
That's where I'm at.
I think with this, and I think my
experience, my experience shows has showed
me my experience with
the whole twit issue.
My experience showed me that as a tech, as
a, as a capable tech enthusiast,
I don't have a solution to this
problem that does not involve
going and writing a whole
bunch of custom software.
And I just think that that's, that
makes, that makes me
feel a little worried.
I feel like this should
be an easier problem
to solve for a tech.
I mean, if you got tech know-how,
this ought to be easier actually.
I do have the heart out though.
So I'm going to.
Yeah.
Uh, yes.
Yes.
I agree.
Um, let's thank some people.
Hold on a second.
Um, and let me just test something
before we, before we end.
Podcasts are cool.
Okay.
So I'll make sure it works.
Podcasts are cool.
Stop.
Yes, they are.
They are very cool.
Uh, let's see.
Where are we?
Value for value coming in during the show.
Unfortunately, uh, didn't get any pew pews
because of the, uh, the routing system.
I was also trying to queue up an end of
show ISO, which you didn't hear, but it
did go through on the stream.
So there's a lot of things
I still need to debug.
Welcome to Linux.
Uh, C-Loss VT, uh, comes
in with 4,300 sats.
Thank you.
A test from true fans.
And you can see it comes from true fans.
Uh, salty crayon, 5,000 sats.
No note.
And 333 salty crayon as well.
Gemini is broke.
They're using F1 as advertising.
I haven't, I haven't seen any ads.
I don't know exactly what F1 is.
Well, yes, but I haven't seen
formula one or any ads on Gemini.
Open AI is broke.
They have to use ads now as well.
Yes.
I mean, that's yeah, they're of
course they're going to have
to go to ads unless people
start paying for it.
Uh, two, three, four,
five from Dred Scott.
He says, go podcasting.
420 sats from Martin
Lindus Kog Lyceum co-listening with Sam
Sethi on true fans.fm having a cup of,
what are you drinking?
Oh, oh, I see.
So now you can do listening
parties on true fans.
That's good.
That's a cool idea.
Uh, another one from salty crayon, uh,
this time from pod verse 245 sats.
Howdy Dave.
Yesterday, an insider in
tune admin deleted 16,000
devices on multiple DOW installations.
Mine was one of them.
Weekend IT surgery.
It's happened because they
centralized this so easily
for any disgruntled admin to take
it down. What's a DOW installation?
Woo.
Um, well, I mean, he's talking about in
tune that's, that's the MDM, um, uh, like
management, you know, where you
can manage remote devices through.
Yeah.
Wow.
Oh, I can only imagine setting
that up for 16,000 devices.
Holy moly.
That's brutal.
That is brutal.
Uh, and he sent the same message through,
um, uh, podcast guru with 333 sats.
Thank you very much.
And I hit the delimiter.
So it's up to you, Dave.
Oh, uh, we got, um, let's
see, we got some PayPal.
So we got, these are all mixed in cause
I didn't, I didn't print them off.
Uh, we got a Jorge Hernandez, uh, $5.
Thank you, Jorge.
Michael Goggin, uh, $5.
We got, uh, uh, Johns
Creek studios, LLC, $5.
Thank you.
Nice.
Uh, we got a one-off.
This is a $10 from Mark Van Patten.
That sounds Dutch.
Uh, he's not actually, but
he does a lot of the end
of show mixes and for, uh, for no,
he's a, he's a end of show mix,
uh, AI aficionado.
And I've set him up with a,
uh, with a streaming server.
It's get mode jams.com.
And you can listen to
lots of AI slop on that.
No.
Yeah.
Well, thank you.
Um, thank you from the non-Dutch.
Uh, my, um, oh, Mike
Newman, $11 and 33 cents.
He says, go podcasting.
Thanks, Mike.
Let me check and see if it works.
Yes, it works.
Hey, from the cart wall,
baby from the cart wall.
Yeah.
Nice.
Dreb Scott, $15.
Thank you, Dreb.
Appreciate you.
Uh, Chris Bernardic, $5.
Uh, Michael Kimmerer, $5.33.
Uh, Saggio Management Group, $50.
So one of our newer subscribers.
Thank you, Saggio.
Oh, nice.
Thank you very much.
Uh, 55-0?
Yeah.
I hit him with a big baller for a second.
Baller, 20-inch blades on the Impala.
50 bucks.
That's baller territory.
Yep.
And we got a one-off
from Olus, uh, Pugorny, $5.
Thank you.
Appreciate that.
And, uh, look, look who popped in here.
Oh, would it be comics or a blogger?
No, it's with love from
true fans, Sam Sethi, $200.
Nice.
Thank you, Sam.
Baller, shot caller, 20-inch
blades on the Impala.
Uh, you know, he's got,
he's got funding now.
So he's spreading the love.
Yeah.
Thank you.
We're getting that trickle down.
That's right.
It's trickle down.
It's podcast trickle down economy.
Yeah.
Beautiful.
Let's see.
We got, um, oh, Dreb's got,
let's see, uh, $33.333 boost.
Nice.
Thank you.
Through Cast-O-Matic, $33.333.
That's, wow.
That's a bunch.
That's a good bunch.
Yeah.
That's a, that's a baller, isn't it? Uh,
it is now. It's a baller. Shot caller,
20-inch blades on the Impala.
It's a baller this time.
He says, go podcasting.
Thank you.
Uh, appreciate you, Dreb. Uh, let's see.
So the, uh, Bruce, the ugly quacking duck,
he says, in Southern Illinois, this is
the podcast guru. In Southern Illinois,
just got off work on Saturday evening.
It is 13 here and snowing like crazy.
Nice to have your podcast to warm up with.
Thanks, Adam and Dave. 73s. 73s, brother.
Uh, Franco. They sent us a boost through
Cast-O-Matic. And we, next week we need to
talk about, uh, some of the,
I've got some thoughts about what
Franco's doing with his boost exposing.
And, um, I don't know.
I think we need to get
into that a little bit.
Okay. Ran out of time today. Put it
down on the, on your piece of paper.
I will.
Uh, and they get the delimiter.
Common Street Blogger.
18, 555 through Fountain.
And, uh, Common Street
Blogger says, hola, gringos.
Now, now all of a sudden
he's Mexican? He's Mexican.
He never ceases to amaze me. Yeah.
Adam and Dave, pal of Adam
and me equals Nick the Rat,
got laid off this week and he needs
new job. Yeah. I heard about that.
Tech support, either remote
or on location in New York.
Maybe some listeners of your
podcast have such a job.
Nick can be found on Twitter,
X, as at Nick the Rat,
or on YouTube search for Nick the Rat.
Yo, CSBAI arch wizard.
Yeah, man.
I wish, I wish we, uh, had enough business
to hire him for Godcaster.
We're going to need someone
like Nick in the future.
For sure.
If, if God willing, let's put it that way,
God willing, we'll need someone like him.
All right.
Uh, that's, that's everything.
We got them all in.
That's it.
All right.
Thank you all so much for
your value return for the
value that you received
from the entire podcast index.org project.
You can go there to support us
with your fiat fund coupons,
podcast index.org at the
bottom, big red donate button.
Of course, you can always
send us a boost to
gram through any of the modern
podcast apps podcast apps.com.
And I appreciate you doing the show, Dave.
I know you have a, uh, it's like a
webinar you got to manage.
Is that what this is?
One of those webinars deals?
It's a meet.
No, it's just, it's a meeting.
It's like a meeting with a meeting.
Not a meeting.
Everybody wants to do meetings on Friday.
I will not, I will not be
here next week though.
I, unfortunately I have
a funeral to go to.
Oh, I'm sorry to hear about that.
Okay.
All right.
So no board meeting next week,
but mark down on your calendars.
We need to talk about something
that Franco was exposing.
I don't know.
Franco, how dare you?
Yes.
Right.
All right.
Hey brother, thank you so much for, uh,
for being here as usual.
Let me see if I can get this going here.
Uh, is anything?
Yeah, there we go.
Yeah.
Thank goodness.
Something's working.
Uh, have a great weekend boardroom to see
you in two weeks here on podcasting 2.0.
You have been listening to podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcast
index.org for more information.
Go podcasting.
They'll never be replaced.
These guys with AI.